Guide to the Alexander Mordecai Bickel Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- BOOKS, 1956-1977; Series II; 2.5 linear feet (6 boxes)
  Series II, BOOKS, has items related to every one of Bickel's works. The most common element is correspondence with the publisher, dealing mainly with technical matters. There are also reviews of every volume published through 1975 except The Caseload of the Supreme Court. The holdings of drafts are much more variable. There are several posthumous versions of The Morality of Consent (edited by friends, as explained in a memorandum by Jeannette Hopkins, 1975 Mar 4) and partial texts of The Unpublished Opinions of Mr. Justice Brandeis (annotated by Felix Frankfurter), Politics and the Warren Court, and The New Age of Political Reform. Earlier versions of parts of most of the books can be found in Series III and IV in the form of speeches and articles. Besides the works published or committed for publication, there is a manuscript, "The Constitutional Law Primer," rejected by Harper & Row. Bickel also planned an American government text with political scientists Nelson Polsby and Aaron Wildavsky, but the venture came to nothing, and the related correspondence has been placed in a closed file (APPENDIX).
  Supreme Court History is arranged alphabetically by author of the incoming letters. The other sections are in this order: correspondence (chronologically), reviews and promotional matter, drafts.
  - The Unpublished Opinions of Mr. Justice Brandeis
    - Harvard University Press: correspondence and contract, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Harvard University Press: correspondence, 1957-1958 June (Box 13, Folder 2-3)
    - Harvard University Press: correspondence, 1963-1967 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - University of Chicago Press: correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Reviews and promotional matter, 1957-1958, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Introductory matter: outlines and drafts, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Atherton Mills v. Johnston: notes and drafts, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - St. Louis, Iron Mountain & Southern Ry. v. Starbird: notes, drafts, and correspondence, 1955, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Strathearn S. S. Co. v. Dillon: notes and drafts, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Stratton v. St. Louis Southwestern Ry.: notes and drafts, undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Other cases: notes and memoranda, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - The Least Dangerous Branch
    - Draft prospectus, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Jeannette Hopkins, editor, Harcourt, Brace and Company: correspondence, 1956-1961 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Bobbs-Merrill Co.: correspondence, 1961 November-1967 Jan, October- 1974 November (Box 13, Folder 13-18)
    - Reviews, 1963-1964, 1966, 1970, undated (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Politics and the Warren Court
    - Harper & Row: correspondence, 1964 July - 1967 May, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 20-24)
    - Assignments of copyright, 1965 January-June (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Edited typescript, miscellaneous and pages 1-30, 1965 (Box 13a, Folder 25a)
    - Edited typescript, pages 31-120, 1965 (Box 13a, Folder 25b)
    - Edited typescript, pages 121-200, 1965 (Box 13a, Folder 25c)
    - Edited typescript, pages 201-270, 1965 (Box 13a, Folder 25)
    - Edited typescript, pages 271-336, 1965 (Box 13a, Folder 25e)
    - Proofs, 1965 (Box 13a, Folder 25)
    - Reviews and promotional matter, 1965-1966, undated (Box 13a, Folder 26)
  - The New Age of Political Reform
    - Harper & Row: correspondence and contract, 1968 (Box 13a, Folder 27)
    - Harper & Row: correspondence, 1969 February-1970 February (Box 13a, Folder 28)
    - Reviews and promotional matter, 1969, undated (Box 13a, Folder 29)
    - Draft of chapters 1 and 2, 1968 pre-November (Box 13a, Folder 30)
  - The Supreme Court and the Idea of Progress
    - Harper & Row: correspondence and contract, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Harper & Row: correspondence, 1969 February - 1973 October (Box 14, Folder 32-37)
    - Reviews in publications for lawyers, 1970-1971 (Box 14, Folder 38)
    - Reviews in other periodicals, 1970-1971 (Box 14, Folder 39)
    - Reviews in newspapers, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - Reform and Continuity
    - Harper & Row: correspondence, 1970-1972 (Box 14, Folder 41)
  - The Caseload of the Supreme Court: And What, If Anything, to Do about it
    - American Enterprise Institute: correspondence, 1973 June-December (Box 14, Folder 42)
    - Publicity, 1973 fall (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - The Morality of Consent
    - Jeannette Hopkins: correspondence, 1972 December - 1974 Jun, 1974 October- 1975 February (Box 14, Folder 43-46)
    - Jeannette Hopkins and Yale University Press: correspondence, 1975 March 3-12, March 14-May 30, June-1977 September (Box 14, Folder 47-50)
    - Reviews and promotional matter, 1974-1976 (Box 14, Folder 51)
    - Edited pages from source writings (set A, folder 1 of 3), 1974 October-November (Box 15, Folder 52)
    - Edited pages from source writings (set A, folder 2 of 3), 1974 October-November (Box 15, Folder 53)
    - Edited pages from source writings (set A, folder 3 of 3), 1974 October-November (Box 15, Folder 54)
    - Edited pages from source writings (set B), 1974 October-November (Box 15, Folder 55)
    - Edited pages from source writings: "Domesticated Civil Disobedience", 1974 October-November (Box 15, Folder 56)
    - Edited pages from source writings: "Civil Disobedience, Revolution, and the Legal Order", 1974 October-November (Box 15, Folder 57)
    - Edited pages from source writings: "Moral Authority, the University, and the Intellectual", 1974 October-November (Box 15, Folder 58)
    - Copy for first typed draft: "Constitutionalism and the Political Process", 1974 October-November (Box 15, Folder 59)
    - Copy for first typed draft: "A Citizen or Person?", 1974 October-November (Box 15, Folder 60)
    - Copy for first typed draft: "Domesticated Civil Disobedience", 1974 October-November (Box 15, Folder 61)
    - Copy for first typed draft: edited brief in the Pentagon Papers case, 1974 October-November (Box 15, Folder 62)
    - "First draft," five-chapter version: chapters 1, 3, 5, 1974 November (Box 15, Folder 63)
    - "First Draft," six-chapter version: chapters 1-3, 1974 November (Box 15, Folder 64)
    - "First Draft," six-chapter version: chapter 4, 1974 November (Box 15, Folder 65)
    - "First Draft," six-chapter version: chapters 5-6, 1974 November (Box 15, Folder 66)
    - "First Draft," six-chapter version, partial, edited, and letters, 1975 January (Box 15, Folder 67)
    - Rough copy for revised draft, pages 1-63, 1975 January-February (Box 15, Folder 68)
    - Rough copy for revised draft, pages 64-128, 1975 January-February (Box 15, Folder 69)
    - Rough, copy for revised draft, pages 129-148 and following, 1975 January-February (Box 15, Folder 70)
    - Clean copy for revised draft: chapters 1-2, 1975 January-February (Box 15, Folder 71)
    - Clean copy for revised draft: chapter 3, 1975 January-February (Box 15, Folder 72)
    - Clean copy for revised draft: chapters 4-5, 1975 January-February (Box 15, Folder 73)
    - "Revised Draft," pages 1-70, 1975 February (Box 15, Folder 74)
    - "Revised Draft," pages 71-150, 1975 February (Box 15, Folder 75)
    - "Revised Draft," edited, pages 1-80, 1975 March (Box 17, Folder 76)
    - "Revised Draft," edited, pages 81-150, 1975 March (Box 17, Folder 77)
    - "Revised Draft," edited for printer, pages 1-80, 1975 post-March (Box 17, Folder 78)
    - "Revised Draft," edited for printer, pages 81-150, 1975 post-March (Box 17, Folder 79)
    - Proofs of acknowledgments, undated (Box 17, Folder 80)
  - Supreme Court History
    - Allaway, Jean, Assistant Librarian's Office, Library of Congress: correspondence, 1966, 1970-1971 (Box 17, Folder 81)
    - Blickensderfer, Joseph, administrative editor, Permanent Committee for the Oliver Wendell Holmes Devise: correspondence, 1958-1960 (Box 17, Folder 81)
    - Dunlap, Lloyd A., administrative editor, Permanent Committee for the Oliver Wendell Holmes Devise: Correspondence, 1961-1966 (Box 17, Folder 82)
    - Library of Congress: correspondence, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 83)
    - Library of Congress, Manuscripts Division: finding aids, 1950, 1958-1960, undated (Box 17, Folder 83)
    - MacMillan Company: correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 17, Folder 83)
    - Mumford, L. Quincy, chairman, Permanent Committee for the Oliver Wendell Holmes Devise: correspondence, 1957-1972 (Box 17, Folder 84)
    - Permanent Committee for the Oliver Wendell Holmes Devise:
      - "Report on Meeting of Authors", 1957-1959 (Box 17, Folder 85)
      - Annual Report, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 85)
    - Permanent Committee for the Oliver Wendell Holmes Devise: memoranda for authors, 1958-1960 (Box 17, Folder 86)
    - Research assistants: correspondence, 1960-1964 (Box 17, Folder 87)
    - Research assistants: notes, undated (Box 17, Folder 88)
    - U. S. Department of Justice: letters and memorandum, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 89)
    - U. S. Supreme Court: guides to records and personnel, undated (Box 17, Folder 90)
  - The Constitutional Law Primer
    - Draft, pages 1-65, undated (Box 17, Folder 91)
    - Draft, pages 66-129, undated (Box 17, Folder 92)
- SHORTER WRITINGS, 1954-1974; Series III; .25 linear feet (7 boxes)
  Series III, SHORTER WRITINGS, has three sections: The New Republic, Legal Articles and Journalism, and Book Reviews. The second of these combines "Articles in Legal Periodicals and in Books" and "Articles in Other Publications" in the printed bibliography.[1] "Most of Bickel's works are represented. For every title listed there is at least one form of the text ear sheets, a copy of the manuscript submitted to the editor, or (in relatively few cases) an earlier draft. In most instances there is correspondence with the editor, usually dealing more with technical matters than with content. There are also occasional letters from readers, but the reactions of public figures and of Bickel's friends and colleagues can be found instead in Series I. When an article credited to Bickel in the printed bibliography does not appear in the folder listing, it may be that no text was found in the papers, in which case any correspondence is in Series I; but some publications originated as addresses sponsored by the organizations that published them, in which case a manuscript of the text can usually be found in Series IV. Pieces written for publication but not printed are included in the appropriate sections.
  Bickel was an editor of The New Republic as well as a contributor of signed articles and book reviews, and he occasionally corresponded with other editors about policy. His authorship of unsigned editorials is almost always shown by the survival of his draft or by his having marked his contribution on a tear sheet, but the appearance of a title in the folder listing should not be taken as proof of even partial authorship, He organized his New Republic files by subject, and he may have kept pieces written by others to complete his record of the journal's editorial stance, His editorials cover a wider range of legal subjects than his books, speeches, and signed articles.
  The titles in each section are: in chronological order, with unpublished items at the end. The papers related to each title are in this order: correspondence with the publisher, draft (except that multiple drafts may be interfiled with the correspondence), tear sheets, correspondence with readers, published response to critics, and research material. The New Republic begins with general correspondence.
  - The New Republic
    - Correspondence, 1956 April-1963 Jan, 1963 April-1966 Jul, September-1970 Nov, 1971 February-1974 April (Box 18, Folder 1-10)
    - "Chief Justice Warren and the Presidency", 1956 January 23 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - "Ninety-Six Congressmen versus the Nine Justices", 1956 April 23 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - "Integration: The Second Year in Perspective", 1956 October (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - "Passion and Patience: Centennial-year Thoughts on 'The Brandeis Way'", 1956 November 12 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Letter to the editor in reply to Hans Morgenthau, 1956 December 31 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - "On the Retirement of Justice Reed", 1957 March 4 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - "Whittaker to the Court", 1957 March 18 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - "Arkansas", 1957 September 16 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - "Eisenhower, Faubus and the Court", 1957 September 30 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - "The Hearts of Men" (Little Rock), 1957 October 7 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - "Yellow Television" (Little Rock), 1957 October 14 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - "No, Virginia" (school desegregation), 1957 November 4 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - "A Communication: Paths to Desegregation" (reply to Charles L. Black, Jr.), 1957 November 4 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - "Brownell's Departure", 1957 November 11 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - "Justice Frankfurter at Seventy-Five", 1957 November 18 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - "Lecture One" (defense), 1957 November 18 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - "How Far offshore?" (oil), 1957 December 2 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - "Responsible Rule and the President", 1957 December 16 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - "Private Wires" (wiretapping), 1957 December 23 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - "All Save Two" (wiretapping), 1958 January 27 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - "Our Guilty Advertisers", 1958 February 10 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - "Dirty Business" (House investigation of the FCC), 1958 March 3 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - "Misleading the President" (FCC), 1958 March 17 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - "Unevenhanded Justice" (Supreme Court), 1958 March 17 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - "Power of the Police" ( Mallory ), 1958 April 7 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - "Judge Kaufman's Rise" ( Rosenberg ), 1958 April 7 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - "The Butler Bill" (Supreme Court), 1958 May 26 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - "The Court on the Right to a Passport", 1958 June 30 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - "The Rosenberg Case", 1958 June 30 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - "Retreat at Little Rock", 1958 July 7 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - "The Court and Congress", 1958 July 21 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - "Our Algeria" (school desegregation), 1958 August 18 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - "Little Rock", 1958 September 1 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - "Without Eisenhower" (schools), 1958 September 8 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - "Lincoln and Faubus", 1958 September 15 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - "Faubus and Almond", 1958 September 22 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - "Rogers and Rankin" (school desegregation), 1958 September 29 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - "An Inexplicable Document" (report of the Conference of Chief Justices of State Supreme Courts), 1958 September 29 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - "The Court and its Foes", 1958 October 13 (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - "The Supreme Court" and correction, 1958 October 20, 27 (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - Letter to the editor: "Should We Stop Filibusters?", 1958 December 8 (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - "Where Once the Poor" (Cardinal Cushing), 1958 December 8 (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - "Defending the Court", 1958 December 15 (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - "Alabama", 1958 December 22 (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - "Congressional Review of Passport Policy", 1958 December 29 (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - "Kennedy's Reform" and correction (immigration and naturalization), 1959 March 2 (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - "The Bar Association" (on Communism), 1959 March 9 (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - "Civil Rights Legislation", 1959 March 30 (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - "Enforcing Desegregation", 1959 April 13 (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - "Objection Overruled" (judicial review), 1959 April 27 (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - "Court-Curbing Time", 1959 May 25 (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - "Strauss and Anti-Semitism", 1959 June 15 (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - "Barenblatt Case" (Communist party membership), 1959 June 22 (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - "Judge Magruder Retires", 1959 June 29 (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - "Mr. Justice Black", 1960 March 14 (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - "Must Chessman Die?", 1960 March 28 (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - "Birth Control and the State", 1960 August 15 (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - Supreme Court -- New Term, 1960 August 29 (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - Integration -- The Seven Lean Years, 1960 October 10 (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - "The Next President and Civil Rights", 1960 October 31 (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - "Mr. Kennedy and Civil Rights", 1960 November 21 (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - "Way Down Yonder" (desegregation), 1960 November 28 (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - "Tuskegee's Negro Voters", 1960 November 28 (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - "Morton Sobell", 1960 December 5 (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - "Robert F. Kennedy: The Case Against Him for Attorney General", 1961 January 9 (Box 18, Folder 36)
    - "Bankrupt Reaction" (Howard W. Smith), 1961 February 6 (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - "Censorship of Movies", 1961 February 27 (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - "Un-American Activities", 1961 March 13 (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - "Parochial and Public", 1961 March 20 (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - "School Aid", 1961 April 3 (Box 19, Folder 38)
    - "Approaches to Civil Rights", 1961 May 22 (Box 19, Folder 38)
    - "Law in Alabama", 1961 May 29 (Box 19, Folder 38)
    - "Freedom Riders", 1961 June 5 (Box 19, Folder 38)
    - "Standing by [J. Skelly] Wright", 1961 June 12 (Box 19, Folder 39)
    - "The Communist Cases", 1961 June 19 (Box 19, Folder 39)
    - Bobby Baker's Silence -- Back to the Fifth, 1961 September 25 (Box 19, Folder 39)
    - "Civil Rights Report", 1961 October 2 (Box 19, Folder 39)
    - "Civil Rights", 1961 October 9 (Box 19, Folder 39)
    - "Mr. Hogan's Decision" (wiretapping), 1961 November 27 (Box 19, Folder 40)
    - "They May Not Travel" (passports), 1961 December 18 (Box 19, Folder 40)
    - "Who May Sit Down?", 1961 December 25 (Box 19, Folder 40)
    - "Wiretap Bill", 1962 February 12 (Box 19, Folder 40)
    - "The Great Apportionment Case", 1962 April 9 (Box 19, Folder 40)
    - "Mr. Justice White", 1962 April 9 (Box 19, Folder 41)
    - "Contempt of Congress", 1962 June 4 (Box 19, Folder 41)
    - "Mr. Justice Goldberg", 1962 September 10 (Box 19, Folder 41)
    - "Wiretapping Bill", 1962 September 10 (Box 19, Folder 41)
    - "Rebellion in Mississippi", 1962 October 8 (Box 19, Folder 41)
    - "Civil Rights: The Kennedy Record", 1962 December 15 (Box 19, Folder 42)
    - "The New Court", 1963 March 16 (Box 19, Folder 42)
    - "Civil Rights Message", 1963 March 16 (Box 19, Folder 42)
    - "Birmingham and the Law", 1963 May 25 (Box 19, Folder 42)
    - "Civil-Rights Boil-Up", 1963 June 8 (Box 19, Folder 43)
    - "Law and Justice", 1963 June 22 (Box 19, Folder 43)
    - "Shall We Pray?" (school prayer), 1963 June 29 (Box 19, Folder 43)
    - "Civil Rights Act of 1963", 1963 July 6 (Box 19, Folder 43)
    - "Civil Rights and the Congress", 1963 August 3 (Box 19, Folder 43)
    - "Wallace Notwithstanding", 1963 September 21 (Box 19, Folder 44)
    - "Who's Responsible?" (bombing in Birmingham), 1963 September 28 (Box 19, Folder 44)
    - "More on Kennedy's Judges", 1963 October 26 (Box 19, Folder 44)
    - "Civil Rights as Amended", 1963 November 16 (Box 19, Folder 44)
    - "Liberals and Civil Rights", 1963 November 23 (Box 19, Folder 45)
    - "The Succession Law", 1963 December 14 (Box 19, Folder 45)
    - "Presidential Succession", 1963 December 21 (Box 19, Folder 45)
    - "The McCarran Act", 1963 December 28 (Box 19, Folder 45)
    - "Liberals and Civil Rights", 1963 December 28 (Box 19, Folder 46)
    - "Beyond. Tokenism The Civil Rights Task That Looms Ahead", 1964 January 4 (Box 19, Folder 46)
    - "Succession Law", 1964 January 4 (Box 19, Folder 46)
    - "Naming a Successor", 1964 January 25 (Box 19, Folder 47)
    - "Warren Commission", 1964 February 29 (Box 19, Folder 47)
    - "The Court Intervenes" (reapportionment), 1964 February 29 (Box 19, Folder 47)
    - "Sleepers in the Civil Rights Bill", 1964 February 29 (Box 19, Folder 47)
    - "Presidential Succession", 1964 March 7 (Box 19, Folder 48)
    - School Aid Bill -- Segregation (unpublished), 1964 March 21 (Box 19, Folder 48)
    - "Picking a Vice-President", 1964 March 21 (Box 19, Folder 48)
    - "Immunity from Criticism" ( Times libel case), 1964 March 21 (Box 19, Folder 48)
    - "Vice Presidential Vacancy", 1964 March 28 (Box 19, Folder 49)
    - "Trial Without Jury" (Ross R. Barnett), 1964 April 18 (Box 19, Folder 49)
    - "Integrated Cohabitation", 1964 May 30 (Box 19, Folder 49)
    - "Opening School Doors", 1964 June 6 (Box 19, Folder 49)
    - "Dirksen Amendments", 1964 June 6 (Box 19, Folder 50)
    - "The Bill as Amended" (civil rights), 1964 June 20 (Box 19, Folder 50)
    - "Communist Cases", 1964 June 20 (Box 19, Folder 50)
    - "Reapportionment and the Courts", 1964 June 27 (Box 19, Folder 50)
    - "Supreme Court Fissures: Seeds of Discord in the New Majority", 1964 July 11 (Box 19, Folder 51)
    - "One Man, One Vote", 1964 September 26 (Box 19, Folder 51)
    - "Is it Constitutional?" (Civil Rights Act of 1964, Public Accommodations title), 1964 October 3 (Box 19, Folder 51)
    - "Reapportionment Rider", 1964 October 10 (Box 19, Folder 52)
    - "Barry Fights the Court", 1964 October 10 (Box 19, Folder 52)
    - "Homosexuality as Crime in North Carolina", 1964 December 12 (Box 19, Folder 52)
    - "II. The Case of New York" (reapportionment), 1964 December 26 (Box 19, Folder 52)
    - "Is the Federal Government Helpless?", 1964 December 26 (Box 19, Folder 53)
    - "Homosexuality, Cont'd", 1965 January 9 (Box 19, Folder 53)
    - "What Has Been Done Is Prologue: Carrying Out the Civil Rights Act", 1965 January 9 (Box 19, Folder 53)
    - "Objections to the Bayh Amendment", 1965 February 13 (Box 19, Folder 54)
    - "Registering Negro Voters in the South", 1965 February 20 (Box 19, Folder 55)
    - "Felix Frankfurter 1882-1965", 1965 March 6 (Box 19, Folder 55)
    - "The Power to Protect" (Selma, Alabama), 1965 March 20 (Box 19, Folder 55)
    - "A Continuing Battle" (civil rights), 1965 March 27 (Box 19, Folder 55)
    - "The Voting Rights Bill is Tough", 1965 April 3 (Box 19, Folder 56)
    - "Investigating the klans", 1965 April 10 (Box 19, Folder 56)
    - "Why the Delay?" (Civil Rights Act of 1964, Fair Employment title), 1965 April 24 (Box 19, Folder 56)
    - "Fifth Circuit Vacancy", 1965 April 24 (Box 19, Folder 57)
    - "Congress and the Poll Tax", 1965 April 24 (Box 19, Folder 57)
    - "Amending the Voting Rights Bill", 1965 May 1 (Box 19, Folder 57)
    - "Judicial Appointments", 1965 May 8 (Box 19, Folder 57)
    - "Speeding Up School Integration", 1965 May 15 (Box 19, Folder 58)
    - "Voting Rights Bill - Third Edition", 1965 May 22 (Box 19, Folder 58)
    - "Judge Coleman?", 1965 May 29 (Box 19, Folder 58)
    - "Freedom of the Mails", 1965 June 5 (Box 19, Folder 59)
    - "The Kennedy-Javitz Voting Amendment", 1965 June 5 (Box 19, Folder 59)
    - "Liberals and John Lindsay", 1965 July 3 (Box 19, Folder 59)
    - "House and Senate Voting Bills", 1965 July 24 (Box 19, Folder 59)
    - "Fortas to the Court", 1965 August 21 (Box 19, Folder 60)
    - "Sex and Nonsense" (Civil Rights Act of 1964), 1965 September 4 (Box 19, Folder 60)
    - "Impeach Judge Cox", 1965 September 4 (Box 19, Folder 60)
    - "Fighting Crime" ( Mallory ), 1965 September 18 (Box 19, Folder 60)
    - "Beyond the Law" (recidivism), 1965 October 2 (Box 19, Folder 61)
    - "Lowering the Bench" (Francis X. Morrissey), 1965 October 9 (Box 19, Folder 61)
    - "Justice in the South", 1965 November 6 (Box 19, Folder 61)
    - "Off and On the Bench" (Francis X. Morrissey), 1965 November 6 (Box 19, Folder 61)
    - "Negro Registration", 1965 November 13 (Box 19, Folder 62)
    - "The Last Act" (McCarran Act), 1965 November 27 (Box 19, Folder 62)